New York State Joint Legislature Committee on the Taylor Law Records 5209
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York State Joint Legislature Committee on the Taylor Law Records
1971
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York (State). Legislature. Joint Committee on the Taylor Law
5209
1.5 cubic feet
1.5 linear ft.
Testimonies.
Include selected testimony, minutes of executive sessions, correspondence and the Committee's final report.
2294703
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 20, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 21, 2017
Biographical / Historical
The New York State Joint Legislative Committee on the Taylor Law was appointed (1971) to study labor disputes involving public employees and, specifically, their right to strike.
In the fall of 1971, two years after a major New York teachers' strike, the New York legislature appointed a joint legislative committee to study proposed revisions of the Taylor Law which prohibited strikes by public employees.
The Committee consisted of Robert Helsby, Public Employment Relations Board; state Senators Theodore Day (chairman), Edward Lentol, John Flynn, Leon Giuffreda, Thomas Laverne, and Waldaba Stewart; and Assemblymen Stanley Herbst, Charles Jerabek, Chester Straub, and Clark C. Wemple. The Committee's staff was headed by Martin P. Catherwood.
Scope and Contents
Includes selected testimony, minutes of executive sessions, correspondence and the Committee's final report.
Testimony includes that of Victor Gotbaum, executive-director, District Council 37, American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees; Albert Shanker, president, United Federation of Teachers; Herbert Haber, director, New York City Office of Collective Bargaining; Ida Klaus, executive-director of staff relations for the New York City Board of Education; and Herbert H. Smith, executive-director, County Officers' Association. Also included are minutes of some of the Committee's executive sessions, its final report, and a fragment of routine correspondence.
The Major question before the Committee was whether public employees have the right to strike and, if not, should they be forced to submit to compulsory arbitration. Other issues included the agency shop, impasse procedures and proposed penalties for strikers and their unions.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Civil service -- New York (State); Employee-management relations in government -- New York (State); State government employees -- New York (State); Collective bargaining -- Government employees -- New York (State); Strikes and lockouts -- Civil service -- New York (State); Catherwood, Martin P. (Martin Paul), 1904-1978.; Day, Theodore D.; Fink, Stanley, 1936-; Flynn, John E.; Gallagher, John T.; Gilman, Benjamin A.; Giuffreda, Leon E.; Gotbaum, Victor; Haber, Herbert; Helsby, Robert; Herbst, Lawrence; Jerabek, Charles A.; Klaus, Ida; Laverne, Thomas; Lentol, Edward S.; Segal, Martin E.; Shanker, Albert; Smith, Herbert H.; Stewart, Waldaba; Straub, Chester J.; Wemple, Clark C.; AFSCME; New York (N.Y.). Board of Education; New York (N.Y.). Office of Collective Bargaining; New York (State). Public Employees' Fair Employment Law; United Federation of Teachers; United States. Wage Stabilization Board
2294703
- A: General Information, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- B: The Size of the Negotiating Unit, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- C: The Scope of Negotiations, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- D: The Exclusion of Managerial and Confidential Employees, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- E: The Agency Shop, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- F: Improved Impasse Procedures, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- F: Basic Issues Under the Taylor Law, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- G: Penalties for Striking Employees and Unions, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- H: The Taylor Law in Relation to New York City, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Committee Correspondence General, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Members - Joint Legislative Committee on Taylor Law, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- New York State Government Employees' Health Insurance Program, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Insurance, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Information, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Originals for Xerox, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Tax Guides: Federal, State, and New York City, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Travel Requests, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Taylor Law Material, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Tax Exemption Certificates, 1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Vouchers Postage, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Executive Session, Joint Legislature, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9a)
- Executive Session, Joint Legislature, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9b)
- Summaries and General Correspondence, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- JLC Taylor Law Meeting, October 28-29, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Summary, General Correspondence, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- JLC Summaries - Exec. Sessions, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- JLC Meeting at Ithaca, September 15-16, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)